Barbara McClintock Papers 1927-1991 Mss.Ms.Coll.79
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1931-1992; 3.25 linear feet
  - Rhoades, Marcus M., 1949-1982 (Box 5)
    See also Ser.I, Peterson, Peter A.
  - The Rockefeller Foundation (Box 5)
    Wellhausen, E.J.
    See also Ser.I, Brieger, F.G.
    See also Ser.I, Mangelsdorf, Paul
    - Folder 1, 1958-1975 (Box 5)
    - Folder 2, 1976-1982 (Box 5)
  - The Royal Society, 1989 (Box 6)
  - Rutgers the State University of New Jersey, 1979-1980 (Box 6)
    See also Ser.III, How chromosomes have been used to trace the origin and migration of races of maize in the Americas
  - Saedler, Heinz, 1976-1986 (Box 6)
    Nevers, Patricia
  - Safont, Julio, 1963-1967 (Box 6)
  - Sager, Ruth, 1949 (Box 6)
  - Salamini, Francesco, 1982 (Box 6)
    Marotta, Renzo
  - Sand, Seward A., 1974-1979 (Box 6)
    Genetics
  - Sastry, G.R.K., 1963-1977 (Box 6)
  - Schiefelbein, John, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Schreiber, Giorgio, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Schubiger, Gerald, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Schwartz, Drew, 1964-1989 (Box 6)
  - Shapiro, James A., 1981-1990 (Box 6)
    See also Ser.I, Dworkin, Martin
  - Shapiro, Lucille, 1988 (Box 6)
  - Sharp, Lester W., 1932 (Box 6)
  - Shepherd, Nancy S., 1984-1988 (Box 6)
  - Sheridan, William F., 1982 (Box 6)
  - Sickler, Stephen, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Sigma Delta Epsilon, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Silk, Georgiana, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Singer, Maxine F., 1990-1991 (Box 6)
    See also Ser.I, Carnegie Institution of Washington
    See also Ser.I, National Academy of Sciences
  - Sjöling-Manger, Anneliese, 1984 (Box 6)
    In German
  - Society for Developmental Biology, Inc., 1981 (Box 6)
  - Society of Developmental Biology, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Sonneborn, Tracy M., 1959, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Sorenson, John C., 1979 (Box 6)
  - Sorrentino, Jennifer J., 1986 (Box 6)
  - Southampton College, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Sprague, G.F., 1950-1951, 1969, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Starlinger, Peter, 1975-1990 (Box 6)
  - State University of New York, 1982-1983 (Box 6)
  - Steffensen, Dale M., 1966 (Box 6)
  - Stephens, S.G., 1948 (Box 6)
  - Sundaresan, Venkatesan, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Taylor, J. Herbert, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Timothy, David H., 1961, 1965, 1982-1983 (Box 7)
    Cutler, Hugh
  - Ting, Y[u] C[hen], 1986 (Box 7)
  - Tokunaga, Chiyoko, 1965 (Box 7)
  - Trelstad, Robert L., 1984 (Box 7)
  - Uhl, Charles Harrison, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Unidentified, 1963-1966, n.d. (Box 7)
  - Union College, 1989 (Box 7)
  - United States. Department of Energy, 1980, 1984 (Box 7)
  - University of Cambridge, 1981-1982 (Box 7)
    See also Ser.III, Diversity of Gene Expression Initiated By Transposable Elements -- Lecture at University of Cambridge
    See also Ser.VI, same title
  - University of Hartford, 1982 (Box 7)
  - University of Puerto Rico, 1982 (Box 7)
  - University of Texas, 1967-1968 (Box 7)
  - Walbot, Virginia, 1987, [1988] (Box 7)
  - Wallace, Bruce, [1965], 1973-1974, 1982; 23.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
    Brenner, Sidney
    Brenner, Sydney; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Crick, Francis H. C.; Cytogenetics; Drosophila genetics; Hershey, Alfred Day; Molecular genetics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Wayne State University, 1983 (Box 7)
    See also Ser.III, Some Unexpected Results of a Simple Experiment -- Lecture at Wayne State University
  - Weaver, Edward A., 1942 (Box 7)
  - Weber, David F., 1967 (Box 7)
  - Wellhausen, E.J. (Box 7)
    See Ser.I, The Rockefeller Foundation
  - Wesleyan University, 1979 (Box 7)
    See also Ser.III, Modes of Action of Gene-Control System
  - Wessler, Susan R., 1987-1990 (Box 7)
  - Whalen, R.H., 1973 (Box 7)
  - Willey, Genevra S., 1986 (Box 7)
  - Williams, Warren, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Witkin, Evelyn Maisel, 1975, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Wolf Foundation, 1981-1984 (Box 7)
    See also Ser.II, Wolf Foundation
  - Yale University, 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - Zuckerman, Harriet, 1981 (Box 7)
    Cole, Jonathan R.
- Series II. Subject files, 1938-1989; 1.0 linear feet
  Programs, brochures, award certificates, newspaper and magazine clippings, reports, meeting minutes, various versions of McClintock's curriculum vitae, and copies of the "Index to Plant Chromosome Numbers" for 1959-1965. The folders are arranged alphabetically by title and include such subjects as the National Medal of Science and the Wolf Foundation Prize. The material about the Nobel Prize includes commemorative Nobel stamps with McClintock's image that were issued in Sweden.
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences (Box 8)
    See Oversized
  - American Philosophical Society (Box 8)
  - Bibliography, [193-]; 4.0 p. (Box 8)
    Bibliographical matters; Cytogenetics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Zea (maize) genetics
  - Birth Certificate, 1943 (Box 8)
    Photocopy
  - Botanical Society of America, Inc., 1958 (Box 8)
    See also Oversized
  - Clippings, 1977-1988 (Box 8)
  - Cold Spring Harbor Symposium on Quantitative Biology: Molecular Biology of Development, 29 May-5 Jun. 1985 (Box 8)
  - Cornell University, 1967-1983 (Box 8)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1965-1989; 32.0 p. (Box 8)
    Bibliographical matters; Biographical and personal data; Zea (maize) genetics
  - Louis and Bert Freedman Foundation Award for Research in Biochemistry, 1978 (Box 8)
  - Gembloux Agricultural College (Box 8)
  - Genetics Society of America, 1980 (Box 8)
  - Georgetown University, 1981 (Box 8)
  - Harvard University, 1979 (Box 9)
  - Index to Plant Chromosome Numbers, 1959-1965; 9 folders (Box 9)
    Genetics of plants; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Zea (maize) genetics
    - Index to Plant Chromosome Numbers, Pre-1956, Apr. 1959 (Box 9)
    - Index to Plant Chromosome Numbers, 1957, Oct. 1958 (Box 9)
    - Index to Plant Chromosome Numbers, 1958, Oct. 1959 (Box 9)
    - Index to Plant Chromosome Numbers, 1959, Nov. 1960 (Box 9)
    - Index to Plant Chromosome Numbers, 1960, Dec. 1961 (Box 9)
    - Index to Plant Chromosome Numbers, 1961, Nov. 1962 (Box 9)
    - Index to Plant Chromosome Numbers, 1962, Nov. 1963 (Box 9)
    - Index to Plant Chromosome Numbers, 1963, Nov. 1964 (Box 9)
    - Index to Plant Chromosome Numbers, 1964, Dec. 1965 (Box 9)
  - Kimber Genetics Award, 1967 (Box 9)
  - John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation, 1981 (Box 9)
  - McClintock, Sara and Thomas Henry -- 50th Wedding Anniversary, 3 Jan. 1948 (Box 9)
  - National Academy of Sciences (See Oversized) (Box 9)
  - National Library of Medicine, 1986 (Box 9)
  - National Medal of Science, 1969, 1971 (Box 9)
  - National Women's Hall of Fame, 1986 (Box 9)
  - National Research Council. Committee on Preservation of Indigenous Strains of Maize, 1958 (Box 9)
  - New York Academy of Sciences, 1985 (Box 9)
  - New York University, 1983 (Box 9)
  - Nobel Prize, 1983-1984, 1989; 2 folders (Box 10)
    Biographical and personal data; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Honors -- Nobel Prize; Lectures, public speaking; Publication
    - Folder 1, 1983 (Box 10)
    - Folder 2, 1984, 1989 (Box 10)
  - Peru, 1957 (Box 10)
  - Plant Germplasm Resources - American Independence, Past and Future, 24 Feb. 1976 (Box 10)
  - Rockefeller University, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Rutgers the State University of New Jersey, 1984 (Box 10)
  - Seminar on Strategies for Strengthening Agricultural Research in Latin America and the Caribbean, 1984 (Box 10)
  - Society for Developmental Biology, Inc., 1981 (Box 10)
  - Soil Testing, 1938-1945, n.d. (Box 10)
  - State University of New York, 1983 (Box 10)
  - Techniques, 1945-1947, n.d. (Box 10)
  - Williams College, 1972 (Box 10)
  - Wolf Foundation, 1981-1982 (Box 10)
  - Yale University, 1982 (Box 10)
    See also Ser.VI, McClintock, Barbara, 24 May 1982
- Series III. Works by McClintock, 1944-1989; 5 linear feet
  McClintock's typewritten and handwritten outlines, preparatory notes, research (including figures and tables), and drafts for articles, books, and lectures. The majority of this series is comprised of lectures, including the notes for the speech that McClintock gave when accepting the Nobel Prize. For each work, the notes and drafts are filed together. This series is arranged alphabetically by title, and cross-references are given for photographs, which appear in this series. The earliest materials in this series are notes on the Maize Genetics Coöperation Newsletter 18 in 1944. There are figures, tables, maps, and drafts for Chromosome Constitution of Races of Maize, a book co-authored with Almiro Blumenschein and Takeo A. Kato Yamakake. Also in this series are the page proofs for The Discovery and Characterization of Transposable Elements, a book of McClintock's collected works.
  Bibliographical matters; Blumenschein, Almiro; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Columbia University; Conferences and symposia; Cytogenetics; Genetics of plants; Honors -- Nobel Prize; Kato Yamakake, Takeo Angel; Lectures, public speaking; Molecular genetics; Publication; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Zea (maize) genetics
  - The Ac Locus, 1949-1950 (Box 11)
  - Activation of Transposons That Function as Gene-Control Systems -- Lecture, Apr. 1977 (Box 11)
  - Activation of Transposons That Function as Gene-Control Systems -- Seminar at Rutgers University, 7 Apr. 1977 (Box 11)
  - Alteration of Gene Action By Genetic Mechanism -- Seminar at Brandeis University, 23 Apr. 1958 (Box 11)
  - Amoeba Proteus as Experimental Object, Dec. 1968 (Box 11)
  - Aspects of Control of Gene Action in Maize -- Seminar at Western Reserve University, 25 Mar. 1963 (Box 11)
  - Aspects of Gene Control in Higher Organisms -- Lecture at Cornell University, 16 Nov. 1965 (Box 11)
  - Aspects of Gene Regulation Revealed by Transposable Elements -- Lecture at University of Minnesota, 17 Apr. 1985 (Box 11)
  - Aspects of the Expression of Genetic Materials in Eukaryotic Organisms -- Seminar at Vanderbilt University, 30 Oct. 1970 (Box 11)
  - Basic Knob Complexes and the Modes of Their Detection (Box 11)
  - Bibliographies, 1981, 1984 (Box 11)
  - California Institute of Technology Lectures, 1954 (Box 11)
  - Chromosomal Elements Controlling Gene Action -- Lecture at Harvard University, 14 Feb. 1958 (Box 11)
  - Chromosome Constitution of Races of Maize with Kato and Blumenschein -- Appendix Figures (Kato), 197-; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Chromosome Constitution of Races of Maize with Kato and Blumenschein -- Appendix Tables (Blumenschein), 197- (Box 12)
  - Chromosome Constitution of Races of Maize with Kato and Blumenschein -- Appendix Tables (Kato), 197- (Box 12)
  - Chromosome Constitution of Races of Maize with Kato and Blumenschein -- Appendix Tables (McClintock), 197-; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Chromosome Constitution of Races of Maize with Kato and Blumenschein -- Data Tables (Kato), 197- (Box 12)
  - Chromosome Constitution of Races of Maize with Kato and Blumenschein -- Maps (Blumenschein), 197- (Box 13)
  - Chromosome Constitution of Races of Maize with Kato and Blumenschein -- Maps (McClintock), 197-; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Chromosome Constitution of Races of Maize with Kato and Blumenschein -- Ms., 197-; 4 folders (Box 13)
  - Chromosome Constitution of Races of Maize with Kato and Blumenschein -- Ms., 197- (Box 14)
  - Chromosome Constitution of Races of Maize with Kato and Blumenschein -- Text Figures (Kato), 197- (Box 14)
  - Chromosome Constitution of Races of Maize with Kato and Blumenschein -- Text Tables (Kato), 197- (Box 14)
  - Chromosome Organization and DNA Content (Box 14)
    See Ser.III, Princeton Unversity Seminar
  - Chromosome Organization and Function in Higher Organisms (Box 14)
    See Ser.III, Columbia University Lectures
  - Clones That Reveal Patterns of Development of the Maize Kernel -- Lecture at Society for Developmental Biology 36th Symposium, 17 Jun. 1977 (Box 14)
  - Cold Spring Harbor Lectures, 1958-1986 (Box 14)
  - Columbia University Lectures, Apr. 1964 (Box 14)
  - Comments on Dr. Roca's Presentation-Lecture, 11 Sep. 1984 (Box 14)
    See also Ser.IV, Roca, W.M., Biotechnology: Opportunities for Agricultural Research in Latin America
  - Components of the Suppressor-Mutator Gene-Control Element, 1980-1981 (Box 14)
  - The Constitution and Influence of Mayan Maize (Box 14)
  - Contribution of Transposable Elements to an Understanding of Developmental Processes -- Lecture, Apr. 1981 (Box 14)
  - Contribution of Transposable Elements to Diversity of Gene Expression During Development -- Lecture at Harvard University, Mar. 1980 (Box 14)
  - The Control of Anthocyanin Pigment Development in the Central Flowers of Daucas carota (Queen Ann's Lace), [1966] (Box 14)
  - The Control of Gene Action in Maize -- Lecture at Brookhaven Symposium, 9 Jun. 1965 (Box 14)
  - Control of Gene Action in Organisms More Highly Organized Than Bacteria (Box 14)
    See Ser.III, New York University Lectures
  - Control of Gene Action: The Locus of the Gene -- Lecture at University of Texas, Feb. 1968 (Box 14)
  - Controlling Elements and Developmental Regulation in Maize -- Lecture at Tissue Culture Association Annual Meeting, 1983 (Box 14)
  - The Controlling Elements in Maize -- Lecture at Cornell University, 18 Nov. 1965 (Box 14)
  - Controlling Elements in Maize: Their Significance in Regulating Gene Expression During Development -- Lecture, 24 Jun. 1981 (Box 14)
  - Cornell University Lectures, 1969 (Box 14)
  - Cytological Evidence of Gene Regulation -- Lecture, 23 Feb. 1964 (Box 14)
  - Derivation of the Venezuelan Complex, Jan. 1973 (Box 14)
  - Development of the Maize Endosperm as Revealed by Clones -- Notes, 1978 (Box 14)
  - The Discovery and Characterization of Transposable Elements, 1987 (Box 14)
  - The Discovery and Characterization of Transposable Elements, 1987; 3 folders (Box 15)
  - Diversity of Expression of Genetic Materials in Eukaryotic Organisms -- Seminar at Princeton Unversity, 12 Nov. 1970 (Box 15)
  - Diversity of Gene Expression Initiated by Transposable Elements -- Lecture at Duke University, Sep. 1981 (Box 15)
  - Diversity of Gene Expression Initiated by Transposable Elements -- Lecture at Public Health Research Institute, 1981 (Box 15)
  - Diversity of Gene Expression Initiated by Transposable Elements -- Lecture at University of Cambridge, Jun. 1982 (Box 15)
  - Diversity of Gene Expression Initiated by Transposable Elements -- Lecture at Weizmann Institute, 22 Mar. 1982 (Box 15)
  - Diversity of Gene Expression Initiated by Transposable Elements -- Lecture at Columbia University, 1982 (Box 15)
  - Diversity of Genetic Mechanisms in Development: Variations on a Basic Theme -- Seminar at State University of New York at Stony Brook, 3 Oct. 1973 (Box 15)
  - The Ds Location. Part III. Transposition of the Ds Locus, Jan. 1950 (Box 15)
  - Examples of Modes of Operation of Known Control Systems -- Lecture, 5 Mar. 1977 (Box 15)
  - Expanding Concepts in Genetics -- Seminar at Cornell University, 18 Mar. 1971 (Box 15)
  - The Expression of the Gene -- Lecture at Thomas Hunt Morgan Centennial Symposium, 1966 (Box 15)
  - The Extraordinary Range in DNA Content and Organization in Plants and Animals -- Lecture, 1988 (Box 15)
  - Gene Control Mechanisms in Higher Organisms. Part I (Box 15)
  - Gene Control Mechanisms in Higher Organisms. Part II (Box 15)
  - Gene Regulation in Maize Revealed by Transposable Elements -- Lecture at Gordan Conference, Jun. 1980 (Box 15)
  - Genetic Components Regulating Gene Action in Maize -- Lecture at University of Texas, 26 Feb. 1964 (Box 15)
  - Genetic Components Regulating Patterns of Gene Expression During Development -- Lecture, 9 Mar. 1973 (Box 15)
  - Genetic Systems Controlling Patterns of Gene Expression During Development -- Seminar at Harvard Medical School, 27 Nov. 1973 (Box 15)
  - Genetic Systems Regulating Gene Expression During Development -- Lecture at Society for Developmental Biology 26th Symposium, 19 Jun. 1967 (Box 15)
  - Genetic Systems Regulating Patterns of Gene Expression -- Seminar at Yale University, 7-May-73 (Box 15)
  - Genome Shock as a Means of Reprogramming Genomes -- Lecture at University of Chicago, 1983 (Box 15)
  - Homeostatic Mechanism Modifying Nuclear DNA in Eukaryotic Organism -- Lecture at Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 29 Apr. 1971 (Box 16)
  - The Homozygotes, 1956 (Box 16)
  - How Chromosomes Have Been Used to Trace the Origin and Migration of Races of Maize in the Americas -- Lecture at Rutgers University, 16 Apr. 1980 (Box 16)
  - How Chromosome Have Revealed the Origin and Migration of Races of Maize in the Americas -- Seminar at Yale University, 16 Apr. 1976 (Box 16)
  - Hunter College Lecture, 27 Mar. 1974 (Box 16)
  - Indicated Relations Between the Central Mesa of Mexico, and of Naj Tel, to the Maize of the Southwest U.S., 1972 (Box 16)
  - Induction of Instability at Selected Loci in Maize, [1953] (Box 16)
  - The Induction of Mutations by Ds: Instability of the Sh Factor Induced When Ds Is Inserted Adjacent to Sh and to the Left of It. Part I. Ds 4864A, 1952; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - The Induction of Mutations by Ds: Instability of the Sh Factor Induced When Ds Is Inserted Adjacent to Sh and to the Left of It. Part II. Ds 5245, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Induction of Transposable Gene-Control Elements, Jun. 1979 (Box 16)
  - Initial Evidence Indicating the Presence in the Genome of Components That Regulate the Action of Genes (Box 16)
  - Innate Mechanisms That Restructure Chromosome and Their Gene Control Systems, 13 Mar. 1978 (Box 16)
  - Instability Associated With Insertion of Ac at the Bronze Locus in the Short Arm of Chromosome 9 in Maize, Jan. 1955 (Box 16)
  - Inter-American Cooperation in Studies of Races of Maize, [1965?] (Box 17)
  - Intranuclear Systems Controlling Gene Action and Mutation, Apr. 1955 (Box 17)
  - Introduction to Control Systems in Maize (Box 17)
  - The Knobless Complex, 1972-1973 (Box 17)
  - Lessons From a Simple Experiment -- Lecture at Genetics Society of Canada, 29 Jun. 1983 (Box 17)
  - Levels of Genome Restructuring by Natural Systems -- Lecture at Pennsylvania State University, 9 Jul. 1978 (Box 17)
  - Maize Genetics Coöperation Newsletter 18 -- Notes, 1944 (Box 17)
  - Mechanisms That Rapidly Reorganize the Genome -- Lecture at Stadler Genetics Symposium, 8 Apr. 1978 (Box 17)
  - Mechanisms That Rapidly Reorganize the Genome -- Ms., 1978 (Box 17)
  - Mechanisms That Rapidly Reorganize the Genome and Modify Gene Expression -- Seminar, 28 Mar. 1979 (Box 17)
  - Mechanisms That Rapidly Reorganize the Maize Genome -- Lecture at Brandeis University, 13 Apr. 1978 (Box 17)
  - Memorandum to Marcus Rhoades, Jan. 1949 (Box 17)
  - Mobile Genetic Elements. History and Prospectus -- Lecture at International Congress of Plant Molecular Biology, 30 Oct. 1985 (Box 17)
  - Mode of Operation of a System of Controlling Elements in Maize, 1956-1957 (Box 17)
  - Modes of Action of Gene-Control of Systems -- Lecture at Wesleyan University, 15 Nov. 1979 (Box 17)
  - Modes of Action of Transposable Gene Control Systems in Maize -- Lecture at University of California at San Diego, 5 Apr. 1978 (Box 17)
  - Modifications of the Genome Associated With Developmental Processes -- Lecture at Public Health Institute, 30 Dec. 1969 (Box 17)
  - Modified Gene Expressions Induced by Transposable Elements (Box 17)
  - Modified Genic Expressions Induced by Transposable Elements -- Lecture at Miami Winter Symposium, 7 Jan. 1980 (Box 17)
  - New York University Lectures, Mar. 1962 (Box 17)
  - Nobel Prize -- Banquet Notes, 1983 (Box 17)
  - Organization and Manipulation of the Genetic Materials -- Seminar at University of Minnesota, 10 Nov. 1971 (Box 17)
    See also Ser.III, The Relation of Controlling Elements to Patterns of Gene Expression in Maize
  - Organization of Genetic Materials in Eukaryotic Nuclei -- Lecture at University of Texas, Feb. 1968 (Box 17)
  - The Organization and Behavior of a Fourth Case of Mutability at the Bronze Locus in the Short Arm of Chromosome 9 of Maize, Dec. 1954 (Box 17)
  - The Origin and Location of Transposed Ds 4710, Jan. 1950 (Box 17)
  - Origin and Migration of Races of Maize in the Americas -- Lecture at Cornell University, Apr. 1966 (Box 17)
  - The Origin and Nature of Action of Mutable Genes in Maize, [195-?] (Box 17)
  - Origin of the Bz weak Mutable Allele, n.d. (Box 17)
  - Arthur W. and Walter H. Page Laboratory Dedication -- Lecture, 25 Oct. 1987 (Box 17)
  - The Phenomenon of Presetting and Erasure of a Gene Locus, Oct. 1980 (Box 17)
  - Plant Molecular Biology Workshop -- Lecture, 2 Mar. 1980 (Box 17)
  - Potentials of the Plant Genome -- Lecture at Cornell University, Jul. 1982 (Box 17)
  - Princeton University Seminar, Jan. 1974 (Box 18)
  - Principles Derived from Study of Bacterial and Phage Genetic Systems (Box 18)
  - Programming of Gene Action By Controlling Elements -- Lecture at Cornell University, Mar. 1970 (Box 18)
  - Pvv Locus, [195-?] (Box 18)
  - The Range in Regulation of Gene Expression Induced By One Class of Transposable Elements in Maize -- Controlling Elements, 1982 (Box 18)
  - Regulation of Gene Expression By Genetic Systems -- Lecture, 28 Feb. 1969 (Box 18)
  - The Regulation Between Maize of Chihuahua and That of Sonora, Jan. 1973 (Box 18)
  - The Relation of Controlling Elements to Patterns of Gene Expression During Development (Box 18)
    See Ser.III, Princeton University Seminar
  - The Relation of Controlling Elements to Patterns of Gene Expression in Maize -- Seminar at University of Minnesota, 11 Nov. 1971 (Box 18)
    See also Ser.III, Organization and Manipulation of the Genetic Materials
  - Resemblances Between Transposable Genetic Elements in Maize and Bacteria -- Lecture, 4-May-78 (Box 18)
  - Restoration of A1 Gene Action By Crossing Over, [1965] (Box 18)
  - The Significance of Challenge in Revealing the Potentials of the Genome -- Lecture, 26 Nov. 1985 (Box 18)
  - The Significance of Chromosome Constitutions in Tracing the Origins and Migrations of Races of Maize in the Americas -- Lecture, 10 Sep. 1975 (Box 18)
  - The Significance of Responses of the Genome to Challenge -- Lecture, Dec. 1983 (Box 18)
  - Significance of Responses of the Genome to Challenge -- Lecture, 7 Apr. 1984 (Box 18)
  - Significance of Responses of the Genome to Challenge -- Lecture at State University of New York at Stony Brook, 4 Apr. 1984 (Box 18)
  - The Significance of the Breakage-Fusion-Bridge Cycle For Inducing Chromosomal Aberrations and Altered Gene Expressions -- Lecture at Gordan Conference, 25 Aug. 1964 (Box 18)
  - Society for Developmental Biology Lecture, 29 Apr. 1968 (Box 18)
  - Some Aspects of Gene Control Systems in Maize -- Lecture at University of Connecticut, 29 Apr. 1964 (Box 18)
  - Some Aspects of Gene Control Systems in Maize -- Lecture, 12 Nov. 1964 (Box 18)
  - Some Aspects of Systems of Control of Gene Action in Maize -- Seminar at Columbia University, 12 Dec. 1961 (Box 18)
  - Some Unexpected Results of a Simple Experiment -- Lecture at Pasteur Institute, 7 Dec. 1982 (Box 18)
  - Some Unexpected Results of Simple Experiment -- Lecture at Wayne State University, 15 Apr. 1983 (Box 18)
  - The Spm System of Control of Gene Action (Box 18)
  - The Stability of the Genome -- Seminar at Cornell University, Mar. 1967 (Box 18)
  - State University of New York at Stony Brook Lecture, Apr. 1983 (Box 18)
  - Summary of Some Significant Aspects of Ds, 2 Sep. 1973 (Box 18)
  - The Suppressor-Mutator System of Control of Gene Action in Maize, Oct. 1959; 6 folders (Box 18)
  - Systems Controlling Gene Action in Maize and Bacteria -- Seminar at Yale University, 23 Feb. 1962 (Box 19)
  - Topic for Lectures, n.d. (Box 19)
  - Transposable Chromosomal Elements in Maize -- Lecture, 20-May-76 (Box 19)
  - Transposed Ds, 1949-1950; 3 folders (Box 19)
  - Trauma as a Means of Initiating Change in Genome Organization and Expression -- Lecture, 16 Jun. 1983 (Box 20)
  - The Tuxpeno Race: Its Constitution and Distribution (Box 20)
  - Unidentified Lectures, 1953-1954, 1989, n.d. (Box 20)